-What are you guys doing up? -Finishing the crossword.
你們在幹什麼？填完字謎再去睡覺
Do you know a six-letter word for "red"?
三個字，也是紅色的一種
Dark red.
深紅色
Wrong, but there's a connect-the-dots in here for you later.
應該不是 不過你待會可以玩連連看
Hey,how about maroon?
赭紅色呢？
Yes! You are so smart!
沒錯，你好聰明
You guys are so cute.
你們好可愛喔
I know.
我知道
See you in the morning.
好，明天早上見 好
I love doing crossword puzzles with you.
我最喜歡跟你填字謎了
Me too.
我也是
Now let's finish this and go to bed.
趕快填完去睡覺 好
Only one left.
只剩一個
Three-letter word. Not dog,but....
兩個字的動物 不是小狗，是…
Cat.
貓咪
You are so smart!
沒錯，你好聰明
I love you.
我愛你
I love you too.
我也愛你
The One with the Cop
本集播出：「搬沙發」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
We still need a tip.
還差小費
All right. Hold on.
好，等等
I got it.
有了…
Nickel.
5分錢
-How much do we need? -Couple of bucks.
還差多少？ 2塊錢
Okay,dime.
10分錢
You guys keep talking. This could take a while.
你們繼續聊，我要花一點時間
Wait,look it!
等等，你們看
This is a police badge!
天哪，這是警徽
Cool. But why would a cop come in here? They don't serve doughnuts.
真酷，但警察來這裡幹嘛？ 這裡又不賣甜甜圈
Could you discover the badge again? I can do better than that.
你能不能重來一次 我可以說個更好笑的
I bet somebody's missing that badge.
一定有人正在找那個警徽
I should take it back. But at the police station...
沒錯，我應該送回去 我去了警察局
...I'll check their 10 Most Wanted List.
還可以看看十大通緝犯名單
My friend's been number 11 forever. This could be her year!
我朋友麗西一直是第十一大 她今年也許會出運
-Hey,you guys. -Hey,Joey.
大家好 嗨，喬伊
Is that my sweatshirt?
那是我的衣服嗎？
Yes,it is. I'm sorry. I was cold. I hope it's okay.
對，我很冷就借來穿了 沒關係吧？
It's just that if you wear someone's sweatshirt...
你要穿應該穿...
...shouldn't it be your boyfriend's?
...你男朋友的衣服
And I'm not him.
我不是你的男朋友
I'm sorry. I'll give it back.
對不起，我現在就還你
It's gonna be all smelling like Monica.
不要，上面會沾滿你的味道
Do I smell bad?
你是說我很臭嗎？
You smell like a meadow.
不是，你有一股青草香
I'm sorry.
對不起
What's with him?
他是怎麼了？
The last time Joey went to a meadow his mother was shot by a hunter.
喬伊上次去青草地 他媽媽被獵人射殺了
Look what I found. It's a police badge.
你看，我找到一個警徽
What's that doing here? I don't see any doughnuts.
怎麼會？我又沒看到甜甜圈
Cops and doughnuts. Come on.
條子和甜甜圈啊
If Chandler had said it you'd all be on the floor.
如果是錢德說的 你們就會笑翻了
Cops, doughnuts? Me?
條子、甜甜圈、我？
I still don't know.
我還是不確定
I want to make sure I bought the right couch, one that says...
抱歉，我想買到理想的沙發 能讓人覺得...
..."Kids welcome here," but that also says...
...「小朋友，歡迎」 同時也能讓人覺得 ...
..."Come here to me."
...「來我身邊吧」
What? You say that to kids?
什麼？你對小朋友說那種話？
The "Come here to me" is, you know,for the ladies.
不是，「來我身邊吧」 是對小姐們說的
Ross, honey, it's a nice couch, it's not a magic couch.
這是張好沙發 但不是神奇沙發
Well,you picked a great couch.
你的選擇很正確
-Sign here, please. -Sure.
請在這裡簽個名 沒問題
The delivery charge is almost as much as the couch!
這是…運費幾乎跟價格一樣貴
That's ridiculous. He lives three blocks away.
太扯了，他家離這裡才三條街
I'll take it myself. Thank you.
算了，我自己搬就好，謝謝
All right, Rach, come on. Let's go.
瑞秋，來吧 好
Are you kidding?
開什麼玩笑
Come on. It's only three blocks. It's not very heavy. Try it.
才三條街，又不是很重 抬抬看，快
Oh,I can do it.
我行嘛
You two will really enjoy that couch.
你們會很喜歡這張沙發的
We're not together.
我們不是一對
Something didn't quite add up there.
好，難怪我覺得怪怪的
What's that supposed to mean?
這話是什麼意思？
Well,you. Her.
你，她
I mean,she's very...
她很…
...you know.
你知道
And you're,like...
而你卻…
...you know?
...你知道
Not that it's any of your business, but we did go out.
雖然與你無關 但我們確實交往過
Really? You two?
真的？你們兩個？
I don't want to do this now. I'm carrying a heavy couch.
我現在不想講這個 我抬著一張很重的沙發
Then tell him quickly.
那就趕快告訴他
Fine. We went out.
好，我們交往過
Not only did we go out...
不只交往過
...we did it 298 times!
還做過298次 羅斯
You kept count? You are such a loser!
我實在…你居然有在算？ 你真沒用
A loser you did it with 298 times!
再沒用你也做了298次
Excuse me,ma'am. You can't put your cigarette out on a tree.
這位小姐 怎樣？ 你不能在樹上摁香煙
Yeah,I can. It worked well.
我可以，很方便
But you shouldn't. So don't ever do that again.
你不該這麼做，別再這麼做了
I won't. Till I have my next cigarette.
我不會了… 抽下一根煙之前不會
Hold it!
站住
N.Y.P.D. Freeze,punk!
紐約警察，別動
That's right. You are so busted.
沒錯，你被活逮了
Book them.
把她帶走！
-Who are you talking to? -Save it,red!
你在跟誰說話？ 別掙扎了
Apologize to the tree or spend the night in the slammer.
不想在籠子裡過夜 就跟那棵樹道歉
I am not apologizing to a tree.
我才不跟一棵樹道歉
You apologize to the tree right now or I am calling for backup.
趕快道歉，否則我要叫人了
Backup! Backup!
來人啊，來人啊
I'm sorry! Sorry!
對不起，對不起
Okay,cancel backup! Cancel backup!
別來了，別來了
Didn't you say there was an elevator in here?
羅斯，你不是說有電梯？
Yes,I did,but there isn't. Here we go!
我是有說，但其實沒有 來吧
Don't you think we should rethink the whole hiring movers thing?
你要不要找個搬運工
No way. They're a rip-off.
才不要，他們會敲竹槓
They check out your stuff and come back later and steal it.
而且他們會先看準東西 再回來偷
-It's true. I saw it on Dateline. -Oh，I love Dateline.
是真的，我在日線報導上看過 我好喜歡日線報導
Jane Pauley is the one woman I would kiss.
珍寶莉是我唯一想親的女人
-There's just something about her. -Rach,can we concentrate?
我不知道… 瑞秋，專心一點好嗎？
Yeah,fine. I listened to your dumb story.
好，只有你能講
Okay,go left.
往左
Left. Left.
左，左…
Okay,you know what? There's no more left left.
已經沒有左了
Lift it straight up over your head.
好，抬高到你的頭上
Straight up. You can do it!
抬高 你行的
You can do it!
你行的
Okay. You got it?
沒問題吧？
-Go,go. -Good,good.
很好
You got it,right? You got it,right? You got
沒問題吧？沒問題吧？沒問…
Any chance you think it looks good there?
你覺得放在那裡好看嗎？
This guy was all:
這傢伙還在碎碎念
And I'm all, "Buffay! Homicide!"
我就說重案組布非
It was just so cool!
真是酷斃了
-You were supposed to take it back. -I'm having fun doing good deeds.
菲比，你應該拿去還的 我知道，但行善的感覺好棒
You can get arrested for impersonating a police officer.
但假扮警察很嚴重，你會被捉
You could get arrested right now!
你現在就會被捉
I'd better take it back. I'm totally drunk with power.
我得拿去還 我被權力沖昏頭了
Yeah. I didn't know you guys would be here.
喬伊 我不知道你們會在
-Do me a favor. Taste this. -What? Why?
喬伊，你嘗嘗看 什麼？為什麼？
It's okay, Joe, she's a trained chef.
放心，她是專業廚師
Actually,I was looking for Phoebe.
其實我要找菲比
Well,you just missed her.
你剛跟她擦身而過
Was that her?
那是她嗎？
-I gotta go. -Joey,wait a minute. Wait.
我去追她 喬伊，等等
-What is with you? -Nothing.
你是怎麼了？ 沒事啊
You're acting strange.
拜託，你一整天都怪怪的
All right. There is something.
好吧，是有一件事
I kind of had a dream.
我做了一個夢…
But I don't want to talk about it.
但我不想談
What if Martin Luther King had said that?
馬丁路德金也這麼說還得了
I kind of have a dream.
我有一個夢…
I don't want to talk about it.
但是我不想談
Look,it involved Monica.
跟摩妮卡有關
You had a dream about the girl I'm seeing? Cool.
你夢到我在交往的女孩？真酷
I dreamt about the girls he was seeing.
我不知夢見他的女朋友多少次
Let's talk about your dream. I love you. Your dream?
總之我們在談你的夢 我愛你…你的夢？
There was no sex. I haven't dreamt of her like that...
放心，沒有任何性意味
...since I found out about you two. More or less.
自從發現你們的事 我就不對她做那種夢了
What was the dream about?
那你夢到什麼？
You were my girlfriend. We were doing the crossword puzzle.
好吧，你是我的女朋友 我們在填字謎
Like you did last night.
就像你們昨晚那樣
That's it. I'm in love with Monica. I'll move out.
就這樣，我愛上摩妮卡了 我會搬走
Joey, come on. That doesn't mean you're in love with me.
喬伊 等等，那並不代表你愛我
It doesn't?
不是嗎？
It could mean anything. Like...
它可能有很多涵義，例如…
...you're jealous that I've become the apartment stud.
你突然眼紅我成為這裡的猛男
Sounds like your dream.
聽起來比較像你的夢
Or it could mean you saw Chandler and me being close and stuff...
或是你看到我和錢德很親密
...and you want that too.
你也想跟別人擁有這種關係
In the dream I did enjoy the closeness.
我在夢裡的確很享受那種親密
If that's what it was,that'd be great. I wouldn't have to move.
如果是這樣就太好了 我就不必搬走了
Are you attracted to Monica?
你現在對摩妮卡有興趣嗎？
Right here,right now, are you attracted to her?
此時此刻 你對她有興趣麼
-Not really. -There you have it!
其實沒有 這就對了
Well,sure! I'm just wearing sweats!
是啊，我穿得這麼輕便
But that's good!
但那是好事
You're not in love with me. You just want a girlfriend.
你不是愛我 你只是想交個女朋友
It's not just about getting a girlfriend.
我覺得不是交女朋友的問題
I could get a girlfriend. We could sit and do crossword puzzles.
我可以找個女朋友 我們可以坐在那裡填字謎
But could we have the closeness like you have?
但我們會擁有你們那種親密嗎
Monica and I were friends before we dated. Maybe that's it.
摩妮卡和我是從朋友做起 也許關鍵在這裡
Friends first?
先做朋友？
That's interesting.
有意思
-You become friends after? -No,never done that either.
你們都事後當朋友？ 也從來沒有過
Do you guys have a tape measure?
你們有量尺嗎？
Yeah. It's actually in my bedroom.
有，在我房裡
That's right.
沒錯
What's up,Joey?
喬伊，怎麼了？
How you doing?
你好嗎？
Excuse me. Is this your car?
抱歉，這是你的車嗎？ 對
Don't park here. You're blocking the entrance.
停在這裡不太好 你擋住出入口了
Don't worry. It's not a problem.
放心，沒關係的
It's a problem for me, so it's a problem for you, because I'm a cop.
我覺得有關係，你就有關係 因為我是條子
So am l.
我也是
完了
Okay. So you're a cop. You can park anywhere.
好，你是條子，可以任意停車
I know,because I'm a cop too.
這個我知道，因為我也是條子
Keep up the good work. 10-4.
好，繼續努力，收到
Wait. So, what precinct are you with?
等一下，你是哪個分局的？
I'm with the 57th.
我在57分局
-I know a guy in Homicide up there. -I'm in Vice.
我認識你們重案組一位刑警 我在風化組
In fact,I'm undercover right now. I'm a whore.
事實上我正在臥底，我是妓女
Who else is in Vice there?
風化組還有誰？
Do you know...
你認識...
...Sipowicz?
西波威茲嗎？ （影集「霹靂警探」主角名）
Sipowicz? I don't think so.
西波威茲？應該不認識
Yeah. Sipowicz. Yeah. Big guy, kind of bald.
西波威茲，大塊頭，有點禿
I don't know him.
我不認識他
Don't try to call him. He's not there. He's out.
不要打給他 他不在，他出去了
His partner just died.
他的拍檔剛死了
Tell Sipowicz I'm real sorry for his loss.
幫我跟西波威茲致意
I sure will. Take care.
我會的，保重
By the way, I'm sure Sipowicz will be all right.
對了 我相信西波威茲不會有事的
I heard that kid from Silver Spoons is really good.
聽說那個新來的小伙子很不錯
Where'd you find my badge?
你在哪裡找到我的警徽的？
Could you give me and Ross a hand moving his couch?
喬伊 你能不能幫我和羅斯搬沙發？
I'd love to,but I got acting class. But you know what?
我很想，但我要去上表演課
I guess I could blow that off. For you.
不過我可以為了你蹺課
Let me ask you something. I was talking with Monica and Chandler.
我問你一件事 我剛在對面跟摩妮卡錢德聊天
Boy,they are really tight.
他們可真親密
I know.
是啊
That's not a bad situation they got there.
那種關係實在很不錯
Think I'll get me one of those.
我也想自己弄一段
What's up,Joe?
你想說什麼？
I think Monica and Chandler are so great...
我覺得他們感覺會那麼好
...because they were friends first.
是因為他們是先做朋友
So I asked myself,who are my friends? You and Phoebe.
於是我問自己：誰是我朋友？ 你和菲比
I saw you first,so....
而我先遇見你，所以…
-What are you saying? -Maybe you and I crank it up a notch.
你在說什麼？ 我是說也許你我可以更進一步
You know,honey...
喬伊
...as flattered as I am...
...你先遇見我...
...that you saw me first...
...令我受寵若驚...
...I just don't think we should be cranking anything up.
但我不覺得我們應該更進一步
I'll treat you real nice.
我會對你很好
Yeah. Well,you know....
你知道嗎…
I think it's a great idea to become friends with someone before you date.
我覺得先做朋友再交往 是一個很好的想法
But the way you do it is you meet someone, become their friend...
但你應該先去認識一個人 跟她做朋友
...build a foundation, then ask them out on a date.
建立基楚，再約她出去
Don't hit on your existing friends.
別對現有的朋友下手
Won't that take longer?
那不是要很久？
Oh,but once you find it...
沒錯，但是一旦得到了
...it's so worth the wait.
真的很值得
I understand.
我懂
Good.
Man,I wish I saw Phoebe first.
真想先遇見菲比
Come here to me.
來我身邊吧
No,no. You come here to me.
不，你來我身邊
-I brought reinforcements. -Great! You brought Joey?
羅斯，我帶援軍來了 太好了，是喬伊嗎？
The next best thing.
只比他差一點
You brought Chandler? The next best thing would be Monica!
你帶錢德來？ 只差一點的是摩妮卡
I would be offended,but Monica is freakishly strong,so....
我應該要不爽 但摩妮卡真的壯得可怕
I drew a sketch of how we'll do it.
我畫了一張搬運草圖
Rach,that's you.
瑞秋，這是你
That's the couch.
這是沙發
What's that?
那是什麼？
That's me.
那是我
Certainly think a lot of yourself.
你把自己看得很雄偉喔
No. That's my arm.
不，那是我的手臂
I see. I thought you just really, really liked your new couch.
我還以為你那麼哈你的新沙發
Just follow my lead.
總之聽我的指示
Come on,Chandler.
錢德，來吧
-All right. -Okay.
好
Here we go.
開始了
All right. Ready?
可以了嗎？ 可以
Turn!
轉
-I don't think we can turn any more! -I don't think it'll fit!
應該是轉不動了 我覺得擠不上去
Yeah,it will. Come on! Up,up,up!
當然可以，快抬起來
Up! Yes!
抬起來
Here we go! Pivot!
很好，中心點
Pivot!
中心點
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
閉嘴！閉嘴！閉嘴
I don't think it'll pivot any more.
我看是上不來了
You think?
是嗎？
All right,let's bring it back down and try again.
搬下去再來一次
I think it's really stuck now.
現在真的卡死了
-I can't believe that didn't work. -I know. Me neither.
居然沒成功 就是啊
I mean,you had a sketch.
你都畫了圖了
What did you mean when you said "pivot"?
你說中心點是什麼意思？
Man,I cannot figure this out.
我就是轉不出來
Yeah, because it's not 1985.
因為現在不是1985年
You guys,guess what? I ditched a cop.
你們知道嗎？ 我剛甩掉一個條子
-What? -What do you mean?
什麼意思？
He caught me using his badge and he tried to bust me.
他逮到我用他的警徽想捉我
Damn real cops!
死真條子
How far did he chase you?
他追了你多遠？
Well,he didn't really. He just picked up his badge and stood there.
其實沒追 他撿起警徽之後就杵在那裡
Maybe we'll see you on World's Most Boring Police Chases.
也許你會上 「史上最無趣警匪追逐戰」
-Why did you run? -I had to.
你為什麼要跑？ 我非跑不可
You know, impersonating a cop is like a Class E felony.
假扮警察是...
Two to four years minimum. I am not going back to that hellhole.
2到4年的重罪 我才不要回那個苦窯
If I can just get it to pivot...
要是能找出中心點
...we'll be back on track.
就能繼續搬了
-Rach,can I get some help please? -Yeah.
瑞秋，幫幫忙好嗎？ 好
Turn it off! Turn it off!
快關掉
Maybe the firemen can help us move the couch when they get here.
也許消防隊員可以幫你搬
-Wait,wait,wait. -It's a new couch! It's a new couch!
等等 不要踩沙發，小心
How's it going? Make any new friends?
怎樣？有交到新朋友嗎？
Yeah. I met this woman.
有，我認識了一個女人
What's she like?
她怎麼樣？
Well,she's...
她的...
...really good in bed.
...床上功夫很棒
-You were going to be friends first. -Hey,it's all your fault.
你不是要先當朋友？ 都是你的錯
Why?
為什麼？
You didn't give me advice. You gave me a pickup line.
你給的不是忠告，是搭訕詞
I told her I wanted to build a foundation and be friends first.
我一說要建立基楚，先當朋友
Suddenly, through no fault of my own, I became irresistible to her!
她突然就…與我本身無關 覺得我難以抗拒
And her roommate.
她的室友也是
What about the closeness?
那親密關係呢？
Closeness, schmosness. There was three of us, for crying out loud!
親密個頭！我們三個叫成一團
Who wants pizza?
誰要吃披薩？
I do! I do! I do!
我要
This is great! Can you believe I found it on the second floor?
贊！這是我在二樓撿到的
-Who is it? -N.Y.P.D.
哪一位？ 紐約警察
Oh,my God!
天哪
Just a minute,officer!
等一下，警察先生
-I'm looking for Phoebe Buffay. -My God,it's him! It's that cop!
我要找菲比布非 完了，是那個警察
-I can't believe he found me! -Are you gonna go to jail?
他居然找到我了 天哪，你會坐牢嗎？
If I go down, you guys go down with me.
我要死也要拖你們下水
Harboring a fugitive? That's one to three years minimum.
窩藏逃犯起碼要關1到3年
Good luck, Chandler.
錢德，祝你好運
Arrest me, but you'll never make it stick and you know it.
好，你可以逮捕我 但你抓不到我的把柄
I have no choice,it's my job. You understand, right?
但我別無選擇 這是職責所在，你暸解吧？
And you understand that I'm calling my lawyer.
只要你暸解我會找我的律師來
And once he puts you on the stand, he'll make you look like a fool!
他會讓你在庭上像個豬頭 豬頭！
I don't like looking foolish.
我不喜歡當豬頭
Maybe I don't arrest you today. Maybe I came by and you weren't here.
這樣吧，我今天不捉你 就說我來了，但你不在
I'd love it if I weren't here!
我不在就太好了
Since you're not going to jail tonight, I was wondering if you'd...
既然你今晚不會入獄 我能不能...
...Iike to go to dinner with me?
...請你去吃飯？
-Me? -Yeah.
我？ 對
Ever since you flashed my badge I can't stop thinking about you.
自從你對我亮警徽 我就對你念念不忘
You're the prettiest fake undercover whore I've ever seen.
你是我見過最美的假臥底妓女
Nice.
漂亮
I didn't see that coming. You're asking me out.
我想不到你會約我出去
I could've done it better, but these people keep staring at me.
我可以表現得更好 但這些人一直盯著我
I'd like to go out with you, officer.
我願意跟你吃飯，警察先生
-Gary. -Gary.
蓋瑞
-Okay, so it's a date. -Yeah.
那就這麼說定了 好
I gotta ask you, though. How'd you know where to find me?
不過我一定要問 你是怎麼找到我的？
You're fingerprints were all over my badge so I just ran it through the computer.
我的警徽上都是你的指紋 我上電腦查詢
And this was listed as your last known address so I just checked it out.
這是你最後登記的住址 所以我就來看看
Impressive.
好厲害
Not as impressive as you. I looked at your record and you've done some pretty weird stuff.
沒有你厲害 我看過你的紀錄 你幹過不少怪事
We'll talk at dinner.
吃飯再說 好
-So I'll come by and pick you up? -All right,I can't wait.
我2個小時後來接你？ 好，我好興奮
Don't worry, I won't just take you out for doughnuts.
放心，我不會只帶你吃甜甜圈
He has a gun!
他有槍
I'd like to return this couch. I'm not satisfied with it.
我要退這張沙發 我對它不滿意
You wanna return this couch?
你要退這張沙發？
It's cut in half.
它斷成兩半了
-That's what I'm telling you. -Did you cut this couch in half?
我就是這個意思 是你把它摔成兩半的？
It's crazy, it is cut in half.
說來很扯，它本來就這樣
I don't understand.
我不懂
This couch is cut in half.
這張沙發斷成兩半
I would like to exchange it for one that is not cut in half.
我要換一張沒有斷成兩半的
We can't accept it in this condition.
弄成這樣不能退貨
Well,I can't accept it in this condition.
弄成這樣我也不能買
You're saying this couch was delivered to you like this?
你是說它送過去就這樣了？
Look,I'm a reasonable man.
我很講道理
I will accept store credit.
我願意接受換購金額
I'll give you store credit in the amount of four dollars.
我給你4元的換購金額
I will take it.
我接受